[A week ago]
Go.
[Nanping City Prison]
And don't come back.
This is some high-end stuff.
See you.
It's been ten years.
You've got an heir now, kid.
Hou Jun.
Mr. Ma.
Look at my memory.
I figured you'd be getting out these days.
I even wanted to pick you up.
But I got busy and forgot.
Alright, alright,
Long time no see.
Come on, come on. Let's talk in my office.
You look pretty good.
You look sharp.
That's thanks to you, Mr. Ma.
Everything you told me to handle before,
I keep it all in mind.
I heard Xia Xue is with you now.
Yes.
I felt sorry for her.
And the kid needs to be cared for.
The child is being well looked after.
That's good.
If you have time someday,
I can arrange it,
and you two can meet up.
As long as the kid's happy, that's enough.
I'll just
take a look from afar.
Now that I'm out after serving
my sentence, I still have things to do.
Alright.
If you need anything,
just tell me anytime.
By the way,
this is all the cash I have today.
Take it.
I am not here to ask you for money.
I know, I know.
No, no, no.
Take it. Please take it.
Take it.
If you run into any trouble,
just tell me,
Mr. Ma.
[THE GUILTY]
[Episode 12]
[Grave of Beloved Son Li Jianjun]
Hello, have you seen Jianjun?
Hello, have you seen Li Jianjun?
Have you seen Li Jianjun—
Come on, let me do it.
Li Jianjun!
You've taken the ring.
We're family now.
Give me two jins.
Here you are, sir.
Don't buy it.
I told you I don't like kumquats.
You have to eat some.
How can you skip fruit?
He was my fiancé.
He also worked at the shipyard.
He used to love buying kumquats for me.
But I didn't like them.
I'd always secretly put them back.
I still don't like them now.
But every time I eat one, I think of him.
People forget easily.
If some things aren't
deliberately reminded,
they're easy to forget.
Some things
don't need reminders.
You'll never forget them your whole life.
Speak.
What do you want to talk to me about?
I always thought
the shipyard explosion ten years ago
was an accident.
But now,
I think there may be
something else behind it.
If it's classified as a criminal case,
that means the real culprit
has been hidden for ten years.
What do you mean
by telling me all this?
I want to cooperate with the police.
You don't have to be so surprised.
I've wanted to do this for a long time.
How do you plan to cooperate?
You stay in the open; I stay in the dark.
I can provide you
with some leads on the shipyard explosion.
After the truth about the explosion
comes out,
you'll learn another truth.
What truth?
About Ma Ke's death.
I knew what you said yesterday
wasn't the truth.
But you can't find evidence
to overturn my testimony, can you?
Yes, that's right.
So I don't understand
why, after finally clearing your name,
you still want to wade into this mess.
Because in that cemetery,
someone I knew is also buried,
and I need to give him justice.
That's the real reason you came to me,
isn't it?
Speak.
What have you found so far?
I remembered something strange
from ten years ago.
Whose car is that?
I've never seen it before.
You throwing shade at me?
Isn't your tricycle good enough?
It's just a Santana.
When I become a lawyer someday,
I'll buy you one.
Alright, then I'll wait for your car.
Hurry up.
Xia Xue is waiting.
Later, I noticed
that after the shipyard explosion,
that car stayed inside the yard.
I thought it was suspicious,
so I checked the vehicle entry records.
I found that one week
before the explosion,
a car
often entered the shipyard as a visitor.
I suspect the owner of that car
died in the explosion.
After that, I used every means
to investigate who the owner was.
His name was Li Hai.
He was from Mingshan County.
[Victim No. 13]
You've told me a lot today,
but I think it's all speculation.
All that still needs to be verified.
Of course.
After all, I'm not a cop.
How's the investigation going?
We found something.
The owner was named Li Hai.
He's been missing for many years.
His wife was named Li Fengxia
and was from Mingshan County.
She died accidentally in October 1999.
Judging by the timeline,
Li Fengxia's time of death
was right after the shipyard explosion.
Wen,
could Li Fengxia have been silenced?
Anything else?
Did you find the address?
Yes.
I'll send it to you now.
Alright, got it.
I'll contact you if there's any update.
Okay, Wen.
You and Yunpeng stay safe.
Don't worry.
Wen, have something to eat.
I'll pass. You eat.
Go.
Bye-bye.
Ma Derong.
What on earth do you want?
I miss my granddaughter.
I want to see her.
Don't come here to see her again.
Or I'll call the police.
None of us will end well.
Xia Xue,
let me give you a warning.
Wen.
That's about it. Let's settle the bill.
Okay.
It's done? Let's go.
Let's go.
Wen.
No need. You drink first.
The brakes failed.
The car was tampered with.
Wu, hold on tight.
Got it.
Wu, hold on tight!
[Nanping Bo'ai International Hospital]
Someone's made a move against you.
You coming to see me
means it wasn't you.
Obviously,
someone doesn't want you
to go to Mingshan County
to investigate Li Hai.
That proves your current direction
is right.
And it also means
someone already knows
your line of investigation.
Have you ever thought about
who leaked
your movements in advance?
He,
do me a favor.
What is it?
Take a look at this person.
Do you recognize him?
Let me remind you,
Li Hai was arrested multiple times
for drug use.
Chang,
help me find anyone
who had contact with drug kingpins
in Nanping ten years ago.
Alright.
I'll ask around.
Do me a favor.
Do you recognize this person?
No.
I don't know him.
You don't know him?
You've seen so many people,
you must know him.
Look carefully again.
Mr. Chang, I really haven't seen him.
I really don't know him.
Alright, sorry to bother you.
I'm leaving.
Mr. Chang.
Feng.
Isn't this Li Hai?
Ten years ago, he used
to pick up from Qiu.
You sure?
After Qiu got locked up,
I never saw him again.
[Harmony Brings Prosperity]
Mr. Chang.
Call him Mr. Ming.
Mr. Ming.
You know Li Hai?
Yeah.
What do you need?
Where is he?
He's
hard to find now.
What do you want to know?
Where did he go?
I want to know too.
He still owes me money.
Besides his wife,
who else could contact him?
Actually,
there is one.
A woman.
Her name is...
Chen Yan.
Li Hai's wife
couldn't have kids.
Later, he got together with Chen Yan.
She got pregnant with his child.
Come on, son. Time to eat.
After he found out,
he wanted to divorce his wife
and be with Chen Yan.
But unexpectedly,
the child was born
with mental issues.
Later I heard
Li Hai went missing years ago,
and his wife also died.
And Chen Yan was left
to raise the child alone.
Her place
is near the embankment in Beishan Village.
Have another bite.
Who is it?
Who are you looking for?
Is this Chen Yan's home?
Chen Yan is my wife.
Who are you?
I want to ask her something.
She's not here.
Just a few questions and I'll leave.
Wait a moment.
Zhuang, go inside first
and wait for me, okay?
After I finish talking with the guest,
I'll play with you.
Come in.
Okay.
Run!
Do you know
why those two people wanted to kill you?
They rushed in and attacked
without saying a word.
They came because of Li Hai.
How much do you know about him?
Get lost!
Eating my food, drinking my stuff,
just thinking about it makes me angry!
Stop crying! What are you crying for?
I don't know.
All these years, you never looked for him?
How was I supposed to?
Call the police?
I wasn't his family.
What would I even say to the police?
Even if I did, what good would it do?
If his wife hadn't looked for him,
maybe she wouldn't have died.
Do you know how his wife died?
That, I don't know, either.
Before he disappeared,
did he contact anyone
or meet anyone?
We were close,
but he rarely talked about his business.
But the last time,
before he went to Nanping,
he got drunk and bragged
about knowing some guy named Mr. Yi
who could help him strike it rich.
What's his full name?
Ming, so you finally
remembered to call me?
Uncle San, let me ask you something.
What is it?
Have you ever heard
of a "Mr. Yi" in Nanping
about ten years back?
I don't know his real name.
I think there was a guy like that.
Then please help me check.
It's urgent.
Alright, I'll look into it.
Xia Xue,
let me give you a warning.
When I went inside back then,
I kept thinking
who wanted to set me up like that.
When I got out,
I finally figured it out.
Besides you,
there was someone else behind it.
What are you trying to say?
After I went inside,
who benefited the most?
Let me give you another clue.
There's a man named Xu Yi.
He was Li Hai's handler.
Ten years ago in Nanping,
on the surface, he did smuggling,
but in reality he dealt in gambling,
prostitution, and drugs.
He's the kind of man
who would do anything for money.
That's all I know.
Because three years ago, he went inside.
Hello, Wu.
Check on an inmate named Xu Yi for me.
He went to prison three years ago.
Ms. Wen.
Everything ready?
Yes.
Are you alright?
Just some minor scrapes.
Let's go.
Captain Qin.
Hey, man.
I've said everything I needed to say.
I've been sentenced, too.
What do you mean?
Nothing.
We're just here today
to ask about something.
About what?
Li Hai.
I don't know him.
Don't rush to answer.
Take your time and think.
I don't know him.
How am I supposed
to remember someone I've never met?
Xu Yi, let me tell you.
Before we came to interrogate you today,
we were already prepared.
Wait, Officer,
please don't scare me like that.
I'm not scaring you.
Let me tell you something else.
Before I came today,
I already let this information out.
No matter who you're covering for,
or what you're trying to hide,
I think that person already knows.
If that's the case,
then I'm even less likely to say anything.
Whether you talk or not isn't important.
What matters is that we came to see you.
To that person,
we've already traced the case to you.
It doesn't matter to us.
This case will
be cracked sooner or later.
But do you really think what comes after
will be easy for you?
If you trust us police,
I can guarantee you this:
I can apply for protection for you,
even a prison transfer.
So if you still don't talk today,
the next people who come
to see you might not be us.
You can't remember him at all, huh?
That's fine. Let's go.
Wait, wait.
Li Hai was working for me.
What kind of work?
As long as he got paid,
he'd do anything.
He used drugs.
And he had a mentally challenged son.
I gave him all the dirty work.
Did you order him to carry out
the Nanping Shipyard explosion
ten years ago?
Lin Hua,
you have to keep the ring thing
confidential for me.
Don't worry.
When are you planning to propose?
Soon.
Why aren't you wearing a helmet?
Which workshop are you from?
Stop!
It's going to explode!
It's going to explode! Run!
What explosion?
It's going to explode!
Why blow up the shipyard?
It wasn't my idea.
Someone came to me and told me to do it.
Who?
I really don't know who he was.
But
he worked for the government,
just like you.
Xu Yi.
Do you know what crime it is
to frame a state official
and give false testimony?
If I don't talk, you force me to.
If I talk, you don't believe me.
Either way, I'm dead.
What's the point of lying to you?
Notify the forensic department
to perform a DNA comparison
[Nanping City Prison]
on Body No. 13
and Li Hai's son.
Wu.
Don't tell anyone about today.
Wen, can we trust what Xu Yi said?
Then how do we investigate now?
You're up so early?
I haven't been sleeping well lately.
You just think too much.
Tonight I'll drink with you.
Where's Shanshan? Still asleep?
She's sleeping.
Being kids is great.
No matter how big the mess is,
they forget it in a few days.
Drink your milk.
Okay.
Why aren't you eating?
I'll eat later.
With so much that has happened recently
why don't you ask me anything?
I have nothing to ask.
You don't even ask
about me meeting Lu Ming?
How many years have we been married?
Eight.
Right.
It's been eight years.
We've been through so much together.
Even though there was no major drama,
we've lived in peace,
and the child is growing up healthy.
That's good enough.
I met Ma Derong.
Ma Derong? What did he want with you?
He said
the shipyard explosion
had something to do with you.
I could've guessed he'd say that.
Given his current situation,
he wishes I'd drop dead immediately.
Xia Xue.
How did Ma Ke treat you back then?
How did Ma Derong abuse you both?
You haven't forgotten all that, have you?
I don't need you to remind me.
Right now, I just want to know
who killed my father.
That case was already concluded back then.
The shipyard explosion
was ruled an accident.
It's all in the past, isn't it?
You eat, too.
It'll get cold.
I'll eat later.
[Police]
Is the meeting content ready?
Yes.
Chief Liu.
Mom Liu.
Didn't I approve your leave?
Why are you back at work again?
I have some leads
on the shipyard explosion,
so I'm here to hold a meeting today.
I know.
I also know you've been in contact
with Lu Ming.
How did you know that?
Everyone in the unit knows.
Don't look at him.
I'll be blunt.
Don't make the whole unit think
you're abusing your position
for personal reasons.
Captain Qin.
We received a tip that Ma Derong
is at a hotel on Dongfeng Road.
Alright, I know.
I'll go make the arrest.
Hello, Criminal Investigation Unit.
Lu Ming?
[Nanping Police Bureau]
Captain Qin's off on a mission.
What's up?
[Police]
Captain Qin, are you still
not fully recovered?
Wen.
I told you to rest at home
for a couple more days.
You just wouldn't listen.
You don't trust us to handle things?
Chief Liu,
why is it you?
Captain Qin's off on a mission.
Go on. What clues do you
have about the explosion?
Do you know Xu Yi?
Back then, it was Xu Yi who told Li Hai
to carry out the shipyard explosion.
And the man who pulled Xu Yi's strings
was the former Security Department Chief.
That is, the current Chief Liu—
You.
Back then, you were responsible
for shipyard security.
You knew better
than anyone where the safety risks were.
The one who knew best wasn't me.
It was Xia Xue's father.
So you planned it long ago,
to make Xia Xue's father take the blame,
didn't you?
Lu Ming, you'd better think carefully.
What you're saying now
are baseless accusations against me.
I have evidence.
Chief Liu.
Captain Qin's suspicions were right.
There was never any tip about Ma Derong.
She led the team out
just to see if you'd lose your nerve.
Lu Ming?
Captain Qin's off on a mission.
What's up?
Alright, got it.
What's going on?
Lu Ming called.
He said he has clues about the explosion
and wants to hand them
to Captain Qin in person.
Someone doesn't want us
to go to Mingshan County
to investigate the missing Li Hai.
Have you thought about
who leaked your movements in advance?
So you also think
there's a mole within the police.
Who is it?
He works for the government,
just like you.
The shipyard explosion
was years ago.
It's ancient history now.
Why are you still obsessed with it?
Leak the news of my meeting
with Lu Ming to Liu Zhijun.
If it really is a cop,
then not only I,
but you would be in danger.
Don't rush. I have a plan.
We already investigated Xu Yi.
At first, we only suspected you.
We called you to the office
just to let you know Lu Ming was here.
If you didn't come,
our suspicion would've been wrong.
We didn't expect you to actually come.
So you and Captain Qin teamed up
to trick me, huh?
Fine.
Isn't everyone here now?
Hello.
I'm at Hekou Pier.
Someone's been shot. Come quickly!
Turn around, Ren Yi.
Officer Wu! Officer Wu.
Officer Wu.
Officer Wu, the ambulance is on the way.
Officer Wu!
Officer Wu, wake up!
[Police]
[Restricted Dock Area: No Smoking
Or Open Flames]
[Police]